(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.2",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
もうすぐはじまるよ
It's starting soon
みおのほうそう
Mio's broadcast
たいき たいき たいき
Waiting, waiting, waiting
そろそろ おまちかね
It's almost time, just a little more
きょうもいっぱい わらっていこう
Let's laugh a lot today too
もうすぐはじまるよ
It's starting soon
みおのほうそう
Mio's broadcast
たいき たいき たいき
Waiting, waiting, waiting
そろそろ おまちかね
It's almost time, just a little more
きょうもいっぱい わらっていこう
Let's laugh a lot today too
もうすぐはじまるよ
It's starting soon
みおのほうそう
Mio's broadcast
たいき たいき たいき
Waiting, waiting, waiting
そろそろ おまちかね
It's almost time, just a little more
きょうもいっぱい わらっていこう
Let's laugh a lot today too
もうすぐはじまるよ
It's starting soon
みおのほうそう
Mio's broadcast
たいき たいき たいき
Waiting, waiting, waiting
そろそろ おまちかね
It's almost time, just a little more
きょうもいっぱい わらっていこう
Let's laugh a lot today too
おはみおーん！月曜日の朝ミオ
[Title: Morning Mio - Monday Morning Mio]
おはみおーん！
Good morning!
見えてるかな？
Can you see me?
はい
Yes...
えー 2026年
Er, it's 2026,
5月11日
May 11th.
月曜日の
It's Monday's...
朝ミオです
Morning Mio.
コメント止まってる
The comments are frozen.
うち、うち、うちだよ、大神ミオだよ
It's me, me, it's me, Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの
From Hololive Gamers,
大神ミオです
it's Ookami Mio.
おはみおはっはっはっふー
Oha-mio-hahaha-fuu...
見えてるらしい
Seems like I'm visible.
よかったよかった
Good, good.
ちょっと、あれだよね
Wait, it's been a while, right?
みこちの
Since I appeared in
すごろくに出てから
Mikochi's Sugoroku...
休んでたから
Since I was taking a break,
自分のチャンネルで配信するのは
broadcasting on my own channel
まあ5日ぶりとか
is like the first time in 5 days,
それぐらいになるかなー
or something like that.
おはみおー
Good morning.
眠いですね
I'm sleepy.
まあゆっくりさせて
Well, I took it easy
いただきましたが
and had some rest...
あの母の日とかもね
Since there was also Mother's Day,
あったんでね
and all.
ちょっと
I went
実家に帰ったり
back to my parents' house for a bit.
まあ逆にね、あの
Or conversely, um...
うちにね、あの
I had them, um...
来てもらったり
come over to my place.
したんですけど
I did that, but...
うちに来てみたいってことでさ
since they said they wanted to visit,
なんかおばあちゃんとかもさ
like, my grandma and everyone
うちに来たんだけどさ
came over to my place.
あ ギフトありがとう
Ah, thanks for the gift.
スパ茶も
And the Super Chat too.
で
And...
声が？
My voice?
ミュートになって
Is it on mute?
ないですが
No, it shouldn't be.
やばい YouTube君ちょっとおかしいか
Oh no, is YouTube acting weird?
今日
Today...
ブツブツしてきた？
is it stuttering?
ちょっとわかんないですが
I'm not really sure, though.
ちょっとそれコメント書いとくからさ
I'll write a comment about that, so...
YouTube
君が調子
...seems to be in...
悪そうで
...bad condition.
音が
If the sound...
変だったら
...is strange...
更新してみてね
...try refreshing.
普通に聞こえる？
Can you hear me normally?
環境によるのか
I guess it depends on the environment.
はい
Yes.
えー ということで
Er, so...
えーっと
Umm...
あの、おばあちゃんとかがさ
Like, my grandma and others...
初めてうちにさ
for the first time...
遊びに来たんだけどね
came over to visit my place.
まあ、なんか嬉しそうにしてたんですよ
Well, she seemed really happy.
なんか
Like...
ミオ頑張ってるね
Mio, you're working hard,
みたいな感じで
something like that.
で
And...
うち猫いるやん
We have a cat at home, you know.
で
And...
ま猫
Well, the cat...
さあ、出てくるのよ。
Well, they come out.
うちの猫は結構ね、なんか全然人見知りあんまりしないから...
My cats are quite, well, they don't really shy away from people much...
ま、出てくるわけですよ。のこのこと。
Well, they come out. Nonchalantly.
君の毎日に 僕は似合わないかな
Could I fit into your everyday life?
匂い嗅ぎに、クンクンクンって。
To sniff around, sniff sniff sniff.
そしたらさ、まあおばあちゃんがさ...
And then, well, my grandma...
白い空から 雪が落ちた
The snow falls from the white sky
お猫はなんて言うんだい？みたいな。名前なんて言うんだい？みたいな感じで聞くやん。
She'd ask, "What do you call the cats? What are their names?" or something like that.
別にいいさと 吐き出したため息が
"It’s okay", the sigh I force out
で、うちがさ...
And I'd say...
こっちがタイガーで、っつって。
"This one is Tiger," I'd say.
少し残って 寂しそうに消えた
Lingers and disappears lonesomely
で、こっちの茶色いのがタワシです。って言ったら...
"And this brown one is Tawashi," I said...
君の街にも 降っているかな
In your town, is it snowing like this?
おばあちゃん...
Grandma...
おばあちゃんさ、こんなこと言うのもなんなんだけど、本当過呼吸になるんじゃないかってぐらい笑ってた。
Grandma... it's kind of weird to say this, but she was laughing so much I thought she might hyperventilate.
ああ今隣で
I only wish…
あんなに笑ってるおばあちゃん初めて見たかも。
I might have seen my grandma laugh like that for the first time.
雪が綺麗と笑うのは君がいい
I want you by my side to say "The snow is pretty"
なんか、めっちゃツボってて。
She was really cracked up.
でも寒いねって嬉しそうなのも
And to look happy and say "it’s cold"
異常に笑ってて。
She was laughing abnormally.
転びそうになって掴んだ手のその先で
I want to clasp the hand as I catch you from falling over
大丈夫かなって、ちょっと心配になるぐらい笑ってた。
I was even getting a bit worried if she was okay, that's how much she was laughing.
ありがとうって楽しそうなのも
"Thank you", you say excitedly
それも君がいい
I only want those memories with you
なんか、なんでよりによってそんな名前にしなくていいのに、みたいな。
Like, "Why did you have to give them such a name out of all names," or something.
タワシの、タワシ、タワシの色だからって。
"Because it's the color of a tawashi," she'd say.
いや、ゲラっていうか、そんなに笑ってるとこ見たことなくて。
Well, not that she's a laugher, but I've never seen her laugh that much.
いや、おばあちゃんの笑いのツボなんか分かんないじゃん。
Well, you don't know what makes a grandma laugh, right?
ニコニコはしてるけどさ、そんな笑ってるとこさ、初めて見た。
She smiles a lot, but that was the first time I saw her laugh like that.
びっくりしたわ。
I was surprised.
本当なんか、こんなこと言うのもなんか、ちょっと不謹慎なのか分かんないけどさ、おばあちゃんもさ...
Really, I don't know if it's a bit disrespectful to say this, but grandma, she's also...
なんか、すっごい元気なわけじゃないというか、まあね、あの、お年がね、やっぱりちょっと上の方になってくるとさ...
It's not that she's super energetic, well, you know, when you get older...
入院したりとかいろいろあるやん。
There's hospital stays and stuff.
でさ...
And...
なんか、ちょっと体弱いからさ、なんか、そんだけ爆笑してさ、もうさ、死ぬほど笑ってて...
She's a bit frail, so she was laughing so hard, like dying of laughter...
大丈夫かなって。
I was like, "Is she okay?"
なんか、このまま、このままヤバいことになって、救急車とか呼ぶことになったらどうすんだろって思うぐらい、ちょっと心配になるぐらいめっちゃ笑ってて。
I was even worried if things would go bad and I'd have to call an ambulance.
すっごい心配だった。
I was really worried.
危ねえ。
That was close.
タワシがツボだったみたいです。
It seems "Tawashi" was the trigger.
もううちは慣れちゃったけどさ、タワちゃん、タワちゃんっつって。ね。
We're used to it now, calling him Tawa-chan, Tawa-chan. Right?
猫は普通に匂いを嗅いだり、スリスリしたりとかしてましたけど。
The cats were just sniffing around and rubbing against her.
なんか、たまにおばあちゃんに捕まって、すっごい踏ん張ってました。
Sometimes they'd get caught by grandma and they'd be bracing themselves.
絶対に抱っこされないという意志。
A will to never be picked up.
まあうち猫カフェだからね。ははは。
Well, my house is a cat cafe, you know. Hahaha.
まあでも楽しく過ごしました。
But we had a good time.
美味しいもの食べたりとか。
Eating good food and stuff.
いやそう、いろいろね、お買い物行ったりとか。
Yeah, exactly, going shopping and stuff.
まあ穏やかに過ごしたって感じかな。
It felt like we spent a peaceful time.
画面をさ、コーティングするカバーみたいなやつあるやん？
You know those cover things you use to coat your screen?
なんか、触るところをさ、カバーするやつ。
The thing that covers the part you touch.
あれをさ、綺麗に貼るのが苦手で...
I'm really bad at applying those things cleanly...
まあ、あんまり得意な人いないかもしれないけど。
Well, there probably aren't many people who are good at it.
ギフトとメンバーありがとうございます。
Thank you for the gifts and memberships.
あ、そうそう、保護フィルム！
Ah, that's right, protective film!
で、あれを貼ってたんだけど...
So, I had applied one...
なんか貼る時に下手くそで、
But I was so bad at putting it on,
なんかね、右端がずっと浮いてたの。
that the right edge was always lifting off.
右端だけずっと浮いてて、で、なんか嫌だなーと思いながらも、
Only the right edge was sticking up, and even though I didn't like it,
でもせっかく買ったしなと思って、なんかそのままにしてたの。
I thought, "Well, I did buy it," so I just left it like that.
なんかそしたら、先日お買い物に行った時に、
Then, the other day when I went shopping,
スマホのケースのお店に行って、
I went to a smartphone case store,
「このスマホケースが良いかな」とか色々お姉さんに相談してたの。
and was talking to the lady there about which case would be good.
あるある？
Does that happen to you too?
いや、そうだよね。なんか浮いちゃうよね。
Right? It just starts lifting up, doesn't it?
で、スマホを渡して、そのケースをはめてもらったりしてたら、
And when I handed over my phone to have her fit a case,
なんか「保護フィルムって興味ありますか？」って言われて。
she asked me, "Are you interested in a protective film?"
「あ、保護フィルム、今貼ってるやつがなんか右端が浮いちゃってて、気になってます」って。
I said, "Actually, the one I have on now is lifting at the right edge, and it's bothering me."
言ったの。言うて、右端が浮いた状態で、多分2年は使ってたの。
I mean, I had probably been using it with that lifted edge for two years.
辛抱強すぎるだろ！ずっと右端浮いてるなーと思いながらスマホ使ってたわけ。
I'm way too patient! I was using my phone for two years thinking, "That edge is still up."
でもなんかそう、右端浮いちゃってて気になってますって言ったの。
But yeah, I told her it was lifting and that it bothered me.
2年も！だってさ、保護フィルム貼ってて、
Two years! Because, even with the film on,
うち画面割れないタイプだし、
I'm the type who never breaks the screen,
保護フィルム自体も割れてなくて綺麗なんだけど、
and the film itself wasn't cracked or anything, it was fine,
ただただ右端が浮いてるっていうね。
it's just that the right edge was sticking up.
で、そしたら、店員の人が、
And then, the store clerk said,
「保護フィルムをうちで購入していただければ、貼り直しますよ」って言われて。
"If you purchase a protective film from us, we'll apply it for you."
「え、そんなことやってくれるんだ！」と思ってさ。
I was like, "Wow, you'll actually do that for me?"
まあ、それで保護フィルムを買ってさ、ギフトありがとう。
So, I bought the protective film... thank you for the gift.
やってもらったわけ。貼り直ししてもらったのよ。
I had her do it. I had her re-apply a new one for me.
そしたらさ、めっちゃ綺麗に貼ってくれて、うちは感動した。
And then, she applied it so beautifully, I was so moved.
ずっと右端が浮いててさ、
That right edge had been lifting for so long,
なんか気づくとさ、右端をグイグイいつも押してたの。
that I'd find myself constantly pressing it back down.
「この右端なんとかなんねーかなー」って2年間やってたわけ。
I spent two years thinking, "Can't I do something about this edge?"
「なんとかしろよ、その2年の間に」って思うかもしれないけど、
You might think, "Do something about it already!" during those two years,
ずっと右端を押してたの、スマホの。それがお姉さんの力によってね、
but I just kept pressing the edge of my phone. But thanks to the lady's skill,
綺麗にピッタリ貼れまして。
it's now perfectly and cleanly applied.
やはりね、すごいよ。プロ、プロ。
As expected, she's amazing. A total professional.
もうなんか保護フィルム貼ってんのかわかんないぐらい綺麗に。
It's so clean, you can't even tell there's a protective film on it.
やってもらうのが一番だね、やっぱね。すごいわ、感動した。
Having a pro do it is really the best way. It's incredible, I'm so impressed.
で、うちさ、保護フィルム貼った時さ、ガイド付きのやつで貼ったんよ、ちゃんと。
And you know, when I applied mine, I actually used a kit with a guide.
なんか枠がついてて、それにスマホ入れて、手順通りにやるみたいなやつだったのに、
It had a frame where you put the phone in and follow the steps, but even so,
右上（右端）がずっと浮いてたの。
the right edge was still lifting up.
だから「ぴえん」と思って
So I was like, "Pien"...
保護フィルム貼るの下手すぎーって思いながら
Thinking to myself, "I'm so bad at applying screen protectors!"
やってたわけ。
That's what I was doing.
はい、今日は朝ミオお便りのテーマ
Alright, today's Morning Mio mail theme is...
「暑い時期に食べたいもの」ということで
"Foods you want to eat in hot weather."
皆さんが暑い時期に食べたいものは何ですか？
What do you all want to eat when it's hot?
というわけでお便り紹介していきたいと思います
So, I'm going to introduce the messages now.
はい、カツタカさんからいただきました。ありがとうございます。
Yes, this is from Katsutaka-san. Thank you very much.
ミオしゃ、ミオファの皆さんおはミオ！
Miosha, Mio-fa everyone, Oha-Mio!
暑い時期に食べたいものですが、自分はサラダうどんです。
In terms of what I want to eat when it's hot, it's salad udon for me.
暑さは暑さで食欲が落ちる時でも食べやすく
It's easy to eat even when the heat kills your appetite,
夏野菜を入れたり、自分好みにアレンジできて
and you can add summer vegetables or arrange it to your liking,
暑い時期の定番メニューです。
making it a staple summer menu item.
写真はサラダうどん発祥のお店
The photo is from the restaurant where salad udon originated,
三國一さんで食べたものです。
Mikuniichi, where I ate this.
へぇー！発祥とかあるんだ。なんか右上に、おはぎみたいなやつ乗ってない？
Heh~! There's an "original" place? Wait, isn't that something like an ohagi on the top right?
美味しそう。
Looks delicious.
サラダうどんもいいね、さっぱりで。
Salad udon is great too, so refreshing.
はい、お次行きたいと思います。川端醤油さんからいただきました。ありがとうございます。
Alright, moving on. From Kawabata Shoyu-san. Thank you very much.
ミオちゃん、ミオファの皆さんおはミオ！
Mio-chan, Mio-fa everyone, Oha-Mio!
私の暑い時期に食べたいものは、スターマンもっちりアイスです。
My pick for hot weather is Starman Mochiri Ice.
夏真っ盛りの暑い野球観戦する中で
While watching baseball in the peak of summer heat,
ひんやりもっちもちのソーダアイスを食べる時間は
eating cool and chewy soda ice...
至福のひと時です。みかん氷もおすすめです。
...is a moment of pure bliss. Mikan-gori is also recommended.
はい、出ました、スターマンアイス。スターマンのもっちりアイス。
Here it is, Starman Ice. Starman's chewy ice cream.
これさ、あれなんだよ。当たると、選手のサイン色紙もらえるんだよね。
This one... if you win, you get an autographed board from a player.
ハマスタいた時、うちはみかん氷を食べて
When we were at Hamasta, I was eating Mikan-gori,
おかゆはもっちりアイス食べてた。
and Okayu was eating the Mochiri Ice.
「色紙当たるかな〜」とか言って。当たってなかったですけど。
We were like, "I wonder if we'll win a board~." We didn't, though.
ねぇ、当たりすごいよね。工夫がね。
Yeah, the prize is amazing, right? Such a nice touch.
これね、確かちょっともう溶けにくいアイスなんだよ。
This one, if I remember correctly, is an ice cream that's hard to melt.
なんか、もっちりはなんか... 葛餅みたいなのが入ってるんじゃなかったっけな？
The "chewy" part... didn't it have something like kuzumochi inside?
なんかそんなこと書いてあったような気がする。
I feel like I read something like that.
はい、じゃあお次行きたいと思います。みかん氷もね、美味しいからね。
Alright, let's move to the next one. Mikan-gori is delicious too.
フィリップさんからいただきました。ありがとうございます。
From Philip-san. Thank you very much.
ミオしゃ、ミオファの皆さんおはミオです！
Miosha, Mio-fa everyone, Oha-Mio!
私が暑い時期に食べたいものは、冷やし中華です。
The food I want to eat in hot weather is Hiyashi Chuka.
暑くなるとやはり冷たい麺が欲しくなる。
When it gets hot, you definitely crave cold noodles.
特に冷やし中華は適度な酸味もあってさっぱり食べれるので
Hiyashi Chuka especially has just the right amount of acidity and is refreshing,
暑い時期にぴったり。
so it's perfect for the heat.
店名は伏せてますが、写真は仙台のお店で食べたものです。
I've hidden the shop name, but the photo is of one I ate in Sendai.
いいね！冷やし中華も始まったのかな？始まってるのかな？
Nice! Has Hiyashi Chuka season started yet? I wonder if it has?
冷やし中華な、あのマルタイのさ、乾麺で作る冷やし中華
Hiyashi Chuka... I really like the one made with Marutai's dried noodles.
好きなんよな。美味しいよね。
I love it. It's delicious, right?
去年は確か... あれ、去年誰が家に来た時に冷やし中華作ったんだっけ？
Last year, I think... wait, who was it that came over when I made Hiyashi Chuka?
あ！あずちゃんだ！
Ah! It was Az-chan!
あずちゃんがうちに来るってなった時に
When Az-chan was coming over to my place...
あずちゃんに「ご飯何が食べたい？なんか作るよ」って言ったら
I asked Az-chan, "What do you want to eat? I'll make something,"
「えー、じゃあ冷やし中華がいいかな〜」みたいな。
and she was like, "Hmm, maybe Hiyashi Chuka would be good~."
言われて、「えー！冷やし中華！？いいじゃん、美味しそう！」と思って
She said that, and I was like, "Eh! Hiyashi Chuka!? That sounds great, looks yummy!"
自分で作ったんだよ、確か。
And I made it myself, I think.
マルタイのさ、冷やし中華の乾麺買ってきて。
I bought Marutai's dried Hiyashi Chuka noodles.
でさ、あずちゃんもさ、手伝ってくれて。
And Az-chan helped me out.
あずちゃんはね、うち来るとお料理手伝ってくれるから。
Az-chan always helps with cooking when she comes over.
上のお野菜切ってもらったりとかして。
I had her cut the vegetables for the topping.
二人でね、冷やし中華作って食べた記憶ある。
I remember the two of us making and eating Hiyashi Chuka together.
懐かしい！いや、美味しいんだよな、冷やし中華。
How nostalgic! Man, Hiyashi Chuka is so good.
食べたくなっちゃう。
It makes me want to eat it.
あずちゃんはー
Azu-chan...
基本さ うちへ遊びに来て うちでご飯作ってとか
Basically, for those who come over and ask me to cook,
ご飯食べたいとか言うメンバーは
or say they want to eat my food...
うち キッチンに立たせませんからね！
I don't let them in my kitchen!
逆にね メンバーシップありがとう
Quite the opposite. Thanks for the membership.
あずちゃんはさ なんか日頃やってそうだから
Azu-chan seems like she cooks daily, so...
なんかちょっと安心感があってお手伝いしてもらったけど
I felt comfortable having her help me out.
他のメンバーがキッチンに立ってどうなるんだっていう
But I wonder what would happen if other members stood in the kitchen.
ところはありますね
That's how I feel about it.
お手伝いするとか言われて来たら まあなんか お願いするかもしれないけど
If they offer to help, I might ask them to,
自ら呼び寄せることはないかな
but I wouldn't call them over specifically for that.
冷やし中華 いいですね 美味しそう 食べたいな
Cold ramen is nice. Looks delicious. I want some.
はい じゃあお次行きましょう
Okay, let's move on to the next one.
えだだいさんからいただきました ありがとうございます
This one is from Edadai-san. Thank you very much.
ミオしゃ ミオファの皆さま おはみおーん おはみおーん
Mio-sha, Mio-fa everyone, Ohamioon! Ohamioon!
暑い時期に食べたいものはタコスです
The thing I want to eat when it's hot is tacos.
夏野菜が美味しい季節になるので しっかり野菜もお肉も取れるし
Since summer vegetables are in season, you can get plenty of meat and veggies.
ピリッとしたサルサソースが食欲をそそります
The spicy salsa sauce really whets the appetite.
軽く済ませたい時も しっかり食べたい時もおすすめです
Recommended for both light snacks and hearty meals.
へー タコスかー
Hmm, tacos, huh?
タコスパーティーいいよね
Taco parties are great, aren't they?
なんか自分で包む感じ
The feeling of wrapping them yourself.
タコス タコス食べたいね
Tacos... I want to eat tacos.
これなんか皮も手作りしてる感あるタコスだな
These tacos look like even the shells are handmade.
野菜も取れるしね
You can get your vegetables too.
まあでも タコス結構あの カロリー高いらしい
But I heard tacos are actually quite high in calories.
お次行きたいと思います
Let's move on to the next one.
スターマンさんからいただきました ありがとうございます
This one is from Starman-san. Thank you very much.
ミオしゃ ミオファの皆さま おはみおーんです おはみおーん
Mio-sha, Mio-fa everyone, Ohamioon! Ohamioon!
私の暑い時期に食べたいものは枝豆です
What I want to eat in the hot season is edamame.
さっと茹でれば 暑くてバテ気味な体に緑の香りと塩分が染み渡ります
A quick boil lets the green scent and salt soak into your heat-exhausted body.
ビールも添えればもう優勝です
Add a beer and you're the champion.
あと二ヶ月ほどで旬を迎えるので 今年もお世話になりそうです
They'll be in season in about two months, so I'll be relying on them again.
いいね
Nice.
枝豆ってさ なんか収穫したてで本当に枝付きの状態で貰ったりとか
With edamame, sometimes you get them freshly harvested still on the stalk.
したやつをさ そのまま茹でると本当に
When you boil them just like that...
採りたて美味しいよね
They're really delicious when fresh.
素晴らしい
Wonderful.
枝豆結構健康にもいいんだよね 確か
I think edamame is actually quite healthy too.
旬あるんだよ 確か 夏なんだよね 旬ね
They have a season. I'm pretty sure summer is their season.
枝付き... なんか田舎だとさ なんか枝付きでもらわない？
On the stalk... don't you usually get them on the stalk in the countryside?
なんか
Or something.
これ生えてる状態の根本から切ったろうみたいな
Like, "I just cut this from the base where it was growing."
すいちゃんちの枝豆は あれだから 普通に冷凍の枝豆だから
The edamame at Sui-chan's place is just regular frozen edamame.
冷凍の枝豆を 何故かあねまちが上手く あの 美味しくしてるっていう
For some reason, Anemachi manages to make frozen edamame taste really good.
いや冷凍だよ
No, it's frozen.
なんかめっちゃみんな 美味しい美味しいって なんかめっちゃ言ってるんだけど
Even though everyone keeps saying how delicious it is.
あねまちも言ってたよ いや冷凍だけどねって みんながいつも食べてるやつと変わんないよ
Anemachi said so too. "It's just frozen. It's the same as what everyone usually eats."
はい じゃあお次行きたいと思います
Okay, let's move on to the next one.
すいこさんからいただきました ありがとうございます
This one is from Suiko-san. Thank you very much.
ミオしゃ ミオファの皆さま おはみおーんです おはみおーん
Mio-sha, Mio-fa everyone, Ohamioon! Ohamioon!
私の暑い時期に食べたいものは
The thing I want to eat in the hot season is...
かき氷です。
Shaved ice.
暑い日に外出していると、
When I'm out on a hot day,
かき氷の旗を見るとついお店に入っちゃいます。
I can't help but go in when I see a shaved ice flag.
アイスと違いカロリーがめっちゃ低いのも魅力。
The low calorie count compared to ice cream is a plus.
みぞれにイチゴ、ミオしゃは何味がお好きですか？
Mizore, strawberry... Mio-sha, what flavor do you like?
うーん...
Hmm...
何味が良いかな...
What flavor would be good...
まぁ、かき氷、
Well, shaved ice,
いろんな味がありますよって言われた時に、
when someone tells me there are various flavors,
何味にしますか？
which one would I choose?
うわぁ...
Whoa...
なんかさ、シロップってさ、
You know, they say for the syrups,
その香りが違うだけで、味は一緒って言うやん。
only the scent is different and the taste is the same.
夢も希望もないけど。
It's such a dream-killer.
なんだけど、うちはいつも、
But even so, I always...
あの、メロンを頼んでしまうんですよね。
I end up ordering melon flavor.
他だと何味が良いんだろうなぁ。
I wonder what other flavors would be good.
毎回出てくる... そうなのかも。
It comes up every time... Maybe you're right.
でもさ、うちさ...
But, you see...
メロンソーダとかは好きなんだけど、
I like things like melon soda,
本物のメロンは好きじゃないの。
but I don't actually like real melons.
こんなこと言ってごめんなさい。本当にすみません。
I'm sorry for saying this. Really, I'm sorry.
メロンはあまり好みではないのです。
I'm just not very fond of melons.
あの、瓜系がね、あまり得意じゃなくて。
Well, I'm not good with gourds in general.
スイカとかメロンとかってあまり得意じゃないのね。
I'm not great with watermelons or melons.
あの、食べれるけど、好んで食べないみたいな感じ。
I can eat them, but I don't choose to.
瓜科が苦手で。
I'm just not good with the gourd family.
まぁ、きゅうりは好きかも。
Well, I might like cucumbers, though.
うーん。
Hmm.
まぁ、でも、丸かじりはあまりしたくないか。
But I wouldn't want to bite into a whole one.
刻んであるやつなら好きかも、くらい。
I only like them if they're sliced up.
いや、そう。それで、だから、メロン味で、
Yeah, exactly. So, for melon flavor,
その、本当にメロンが入ってるとかだったらちょっと違うんだけど、
if it actually has real melon in it, that's different,
本当に純粋にあの、色がついたシロップだと、
but if it's just that pure colored syrup,
結構メロンをね、頼んじゃうのかもしれませんね。
I guess I often end up ordering melon.
あー、なんで苦手かって、なんか青臭い感じがちょっと苦手なのかも。
Ah, why I'm not fond of them? Maybe it's that "green" smell.
昔から苦手なんだよね、ちょっとだけ。
I've been a little bad with it for a long time.
青臭さがね。
That green, grassy smell.
いや、ナスはちょっと違くないか？ ナスは好きだけど。
Wait, aren't eggplants different? I like eggplants.
あ、青臭いのわかる？
Oh, you understand the green smell?
いや、そうなんだよな。まぁ、食べれないというわけではないんですけどね。
Yeah, exactly. Well, it's not that I can't eat them.
いや、でも、うーん、でもあまり食べる機会ないからなぁ。
But, well... I don't really have many chances to eat them.
今食べたらまた違うのかな？ わかんないね。
I wonder if it'd be different if I tried some now? Who knows.
すごい、みんなさ、めちゃくちゃ質問してきてるけどさ。
Wow, you guys are asking so many questions.
あの、メロンパンは、中にメロン果汁とか入ってなければ好きです。
As for melon pan, I like it if there's no real juice inside.
みんなめっちゃ、「この野菜は？」「この野菜は？」って質問してきてるけど、
Everyone's asking "What about this vegetable?" or that one,
それ瓜科じゃないからね、みたいな野菜は多いんだけど。
but many of those aren't even in the gourd family.
全部つけなきゃいけない、なんか、野菜、片っ端から書き出して、
I'd have to list every vegetable one by one...
これは食べれる、これは食べれない、これは食べれる、って。
"I can eat this," "I can't eat that," "I can eat this."
いや、でも、食べれない野菜はあまりないかな。ないけど。
But really, there aren't many vegetables I can't eat.
まぁ、でも、なんか葉っぱ... 香りが強い葉っぱは苦手で、
Though, for leaves... I'm not good with strong-scented ones.
セロリとか、春菊とか、青じそとか、ちょっと苦手なんだけど、
Celery, garland chrysanthemum, green shiso... I'm a bit bad with those.
でも、パクチーは食べれるんだよね。
But I can eat cilantro.
なんかパクチー苦手かなーって思ってた時期もあったんだけど、
There was a time when I thought I might dislike it,
なんかパクチーって、あ、そう、苦手な人多いし。
since so many people seem to hate it.
でもね、パクチーは食べれるの。
But I can actually eat cilantro.
なんか入ってても別に大丈夫。
I'm perfectly fine with it being in a dish.
まぁ、好んでめっちゃパクチーサラダみたいなのを食べるわけではないけど、
I wouldn't go out of my way to eat a cilantro salad,
パクチーはなんか料理に入ってても普通に食べれるわ。
but if it's in my food, I can eat it just fine.
なんなんだろう。
I wonder why that is.
え、パクチーってさ、青臭いの？ そうなんだ。へぇー。
Wait, is cilantro considered "green" smelling? I see.
うちはパクチー、なんかさ...
To me, cilantro is more like...
...食べてる人によって違うじゃん感想が
...the impression varies depending on the person eating it.
不思議なんだけど、うちはね...
It's strange, but for me...
パクチーはね、カシューナッツみたいな味だなって思ってるの
I think cilantro tastes like cashew nuts.
不思議だね...
How strange...
だね不思議
Yes, strange.
言わせたがるね...
You really want me to say it...
パクチー食べれる人食べれない人は遺伝子によるらしいよ
Apparently, whether you can eat cilantro or not depends on your genes.
食べれる遺伝子と食べれない遺伝子があるらしい
I heard there's a gene for being able to eat it and one for not.
スバルが日常生活でも使ってるって言ってた
Subaru said I use it in my daily life too.
持ってない？
Aren't you exaggerating?
いやそんな配信でもそういう間やん、そんなに
No, I only use that timing during streams, not that much.
日常生活いつ言ってた？
When did I say it in daily life?
そんな外で言ったことあるかな？
I wonder if I've ever said it out in public?
え、無意識？いや無意識では言わないよ
Eh, unconsciously? No, I wouldn't say it unconsciously.
言うわけないじゃん
There's no way I would.
「だね不思議」で身バレする？
Would "Yes, strange" reveal my identity?
はあ、そっか、じゃあ気をつけますね
Ah, I see. Then I'll be careful.
ま、外で言わないように気をつけないとね、はい
Well, I have to be careful not to say it in public, right.
じゃ、次いきたいと思います
Now, let's move on to the next one.
スバルはそうなの？
Is that how it is, Subaru?
え、それスバルの家でやったやつじゃないの？
Wait, wasn't that something we did at Subaru's house?
スバルの家では言ったかも、会話の中で
I might have said it at Subaru's house during a conversation.
そしたらなんか喜んでたけど
And she seemed happy about it for some reason.
えーと、R2さんからいただきました。ありがとうございます。
Um, this is from R2-san. Thank you very much.
ミオしゃ、ミオファの皆さんおはミオーん！おはミオーン！
Mio-sha, everyone in Mio-fa, Good Morn-Mio! Good Morn-Mio!
私の暑い時期に食べたいものは氷系のアイスです。
What I want to eat during the hot season is shaved ice-type treats.
特に新潟の夏といえばこれ、桃太郎アイス！
Especially when it comes to summer in Niigata, it's this: Momotaro Ice!
桃太郎だけど、いちご味でりんご果汁が入っているという、
It's called Momotaro, but it's strawberry flavored and contains apple juice...
ちょっと不思議なアイスですが、夏にぴったりの美味しさなんです。
...it's a bit of a strange ice cream, but it's perfectly delicious for summer.
へえ〜、そうなんだ！
Heh~, I see!
桃太郎アイスって見たことないかも、あんまり
I don't think I've ever seen Momotaro Ice, really.
桃味じゃないんだね！初めて見た。
It's not peach flavored! This is the first I've seen it.
いちご味で...
Strawberry flavored...
りんご果汁が入ってるの？
And it has apple juice in it?
不思議だね...
How strange...
だね不思議！
Yes, strange!
別にこれ言わされて言ってるわけじゃないんですよ、あの、
It's not like I'm being forced to say this, you see...
頭の中に「不思議だね」っていう単語が出てきたら、あ、
When the words "how strange" pop into my head...
その一手先を読んで、「あべっ！言わなきゃ！」みたいな。
I read one step ahead and think, "Oh no! I have to say it!"
言わされてるというよりは、ま、うちの中の強迫観念ですね、これも。
Rather than being forced, it's more like a compulsion within me.
はい、お次いきたいと思います
Okay, let's move on to the next one.
タロウさんからいただきました。ありがとうございます。
This is from Taro-san. Thank you very much.
ミオしゃ、ミオファの皆さんおはミオーん！おはミオーン！
Mio-sha, everyone in Mio-fa, Good Morn-Mio! Good Morn-Mio!
私の暑い時期に食べたいものは流しそうめんです。
What I want to eat during the hot season is flowing somen noodles.
水の中を流れるそうめんを見てるだけでも涼しくなれるし、
Just watching the somen flowing through the water makes you feel cool...
ちゅるっと食べると身も心も涼しい気持ちになれる、
...and eating them with a slurp makes your body and soul feel refreshed.
素晴らしい食べ物だと思います。
I think it's a wonderful food.
定番だけどやっぱりこれなんだよな〜。
It's a classic, but this is the one after all.
おお〜、すごい！
Ooh~, amazing!
なんか流しそうめん屋さんみたいになってるね
It looks like a flowing somen restaurant.
真ん中になんか置いてるし、
There's even something placed in the middle...
流しそうめん自体がテーブルになってるのいいですね。すごい。
It's nice that the flowing somen setup itself is a table. Amazing.
流れてんのかな、これ。
Is it flowing, I wonder?
あんまりなんか、そうめん流れてる感じしないけど。
It doesn't really look like the somen is flowing, though.
ねー。そうめんもいい、ねー。
Yeah. Somen is nice too, isn't it?
そろそろチュルチュルの季節。
It's almost the season for slurpable noodles.
なんか去年、ちょっと早めにやったんじゃなかったっけ。6月ぐらいに。
Didn't I do it a bit early last year? Around June.
なんかやったような記憶が。
I have a memory of doing something like that.
でもなんか、今年ちょっと早いね、みたいな感じだったから。
But it felt like it's a bit early this year.
ま、もうちょっと夏になってからかなー。
So maybe when it gets a bit more like summer.
ちょっとお水飲みます。
I'm going to drink some water.
レックウザ、フブキの家で元気にしてるんじゃないか？
Rayquaza is probably doing well at Fubuki's house, isn't he?
わかんないけど。
I don't know, though.
いや、あるとしたらフブキの家に、あるはず。
But if it's anywhere, it should be at Fubuki's house.
私レックウザ使うんかな？
I wonder if I'll use Rayquaza?
分かりません。
I have no idea.
はい、じゃあお次いきたいと思います。
Okay, let's move on to the next one.
りょうたさんからいただきました。ありがとうございます。
This one is from Ryota-san. Thank you very much.
「ミオしゃ、ミオファの皆様おはみおーん！」おはみおーん。
'Miosha, Miofa everyone, Ohamioon!' Ohamioon.
「私の暑い時期に食べたいものは、ぶっかけうどんです。」
'The thing I want to eat when it's hot is bukkake udon.'
「キンキンに冷えたうどんと大根おろしの組み合わせの喉越しは格別です。」
'The way ice-cold udon and grated daikon radish go down is exceptional.'
「写真は香川県で食べたうどん、めっちゃ美味しかった。」
'This is a photo of udon I ate in Kagawa; it was delicious.'
いいですねー。
That's nice.
うどんかー。
Udon, huh.
香川のうどん美味しいからな、もちもちで。
Kagawa's udon is delicious because it's so chewy.
なんか違うよね、普通のうどんとさ。
It's different from regular udon, isn't it?
何があんなに違うんだろう、あんなにもちもちしてて。
I wonder what makes it so different and so chewy.
お腹空いてきた。
I'm getting hungry.
いや美味しそうだよね。こっちもお腹空いてきたな。
It looks delicious. I'm getting hungry too.
昨日さ、お昼ご飯がちょっと遅めで、しかもめっちゃ食べたから、
Yesterday, I had lunch a bit late and ate a lot,
メンバーシップありがとう。
Thank you for the membership.
なんか、お腹が全然空かなくて、夜ご飯パスしたの。
So I wasn't hungry at all and skipped dinner.
「もういいや」と思って、夜ご飯食べずにそのまま寝たら、
I thought, 'I'm fine,' and went to sleep without eating,
もうお腹空いてね、今。
And now I'm really hungry.
何か食べなきゃだ。
I need to eat something.
はい、じゃあ次の投稿最後にしたいと思います。
Okay, I'll make this next post the last one.
やまびこさんからいただきました。ありがとうございます。
This is from Yamabiko-san. Thank you very much.
「ミオしゃ、ミオファの皆様おはみおーん！」おはみおーん。
'Miosha, Miofa everyone, Ohamioon!' Ohamioon.
「暑い時期に食べたいものは、カレーです。」
'The thing I want to eat when it's hot is curry.'
「どんどんとお暑さが増してきて、バテる前にスパイスパワーで元気を頂いてます。」
'The heat is increasing, so I'm getting energy from spice power before I get exhausted.'
「年々暑さが増しているので、イベント参加するためにも、」
'Since it's getting hotter every year, in order to participate in events,'
「スパイスパワーで今年も元気に乗り切りたいですね。」
'I want to get through this year healthily with spice power too.'
スパイスね、いいよね。カレーね。
Spice, it's good. Curry, right.
夏といえばカレー。
Curry is the quintessential summer food.
いやなんかさ、最近、あのスバルと奏手でさ、
Recently, with Subaru and Kanade...
ココイチジャンケンをやってたの。
We were doing 'CoCo Ichibanya Rock-Paper-Scissors.'
メンバーシップありがとう。
Thank you for the membership.
で、なんかそれに、その引用リツイートでちょっと反応したりとかしてたんだけど、
And I responded to it with a quote retweet and such,
なんかそれをね、気遣ってか、
Maybe because they noticed that...
ココイチさんからね、
From CoCo Ichibanya...
グッズが……
some goods...
失礼しました。グッズがね、
Excuse me. Goods, you know...
もらえるらしい。
I'm going to get some.
ココイチグッズをね、送ってくれるんだって。ちょっと楽しみにしてんだよな。
They're sending me CoCo Ichi goods. I'm looking forward to it.
メンバーシップありがとう。
Thank you for the membership.
というわけで。
So with that said.
以上、朝ミオお便りのコーナーでした。
That concludes the Morning Mio fan mail segment.
来週の朝ミオお便りのテーマを考えたいと思います。
I'll think about next week's Morning Mio fan mail theme.
来週の朝ミオお便りのテーマ……
Next week's theme...
すごい、もうゴールデンウィーク終わっちゃったよ。早いな。
Wow, Golden Week is already over. That was fast.
時間が経つのは早いな。
Time flies by.
来週は5月の18……
Next week is May 18th...
5月も半ばですね
It's already the middle of May, isn't it?
五月病ってさ、本当にあるの？
Is "May sickness" really a thing?
やばい、こんなこと言ったらあれか、よくないか
Wait, is it bad if I say something like that?
五月病って本当にあるんですか？
Does May sickness really exist?
いやそう、なったことないよなーって思ってさ
Yeah, I was just thinking that I've never had it.
まあでも、なる人はなるのかも
Well, maybe people who get it just get it.
でもなんで五月病ってなるんだろう
But I wonder why people get May sickness?
あんまり掘らないほうがいいのか
Maybe I shouldn't dig too deep into it.
ゴールデンウィークが楽しくて、もう出勤したくないってなるからなのかな
Is it because Golden Week is so fun that they don't want to go back to work?
それとも5月で、逆にゴールデンウィークみんなお休みなのに...
Or maybe it's because it's May, and even though everyone else has Golden Week off...
自分はお休みじゃなかったからなるのか
you didn't have it off yourself?
メンバーシップありがとう
Thank you for the membership!
メンタル的な問題？
Is it a mental issue?
そっか
I see.
それは人それぞれかもね
That might vary from person to person.
うちは、なったことないかも、すいません
I might have never had it myself, sorry!
じゃあ、これにしますか
Then, shall we go with this?
生活リズムの正し方
How to Fix Your Lifestyle Rhythm
あなたが「生活リズム狂ってるな、そろそろ直さなきゃ」っていうときにやる事ってなんですか？
What do you do when you feel like your daily rhythm is off and you need to fix it?
生活リズムの正し方がこれぞというものがあれば教えてください
Please let me know if you have a definitive way of fixing your lifestyle rhythm.
うちは最近ね、えーと、夜ちゃんと寝るように気をつけているかな
Lately, I've been making sure to sleep properly at night.
一応お布団には1時か2時には入るように気をつけてて
I try to get into bed by 1 or 2 AM.
翌日は、まあ、9時か10時には起きようみたいな感覚で
And the next morning, I try to wake up around 9 or 10 AM.
目覚まし鳴らさずにでもね、1時か2時に寝ればね、結構8時ぐらいには目覚めたりとかするかな
Even without an alarm, if I sleep at 1 or 2, I usually wake up around 8.
まあ、結構いいなと思いますその生活
I think that kind of lifestyle is pretty good.
で朝ごはんを食べるでしょ
Then you eat breakfast, right?
でちょっと日光浴して
And get a bit of sunlight.
いやそうなんです、体内時計リセットするのはね、大事かもしれませんね
Exactly. Resetting your internal clock might be important.
あなたが生活リズムを直したいなって思ったときにやる事、教えてください
Please tell me what you do when you want to fix your lifestyle rhythm.
ではお次、朝ミオニュース！
And now, for the next segment: Morning Mio News!
気になるホロライブのニュースを、まるっとお届け、朝ミオニュース
Bringing you all the Hololive news you're curious about: Morning Mio News.
コメントが止まっているので一回直したいと思います
The comments have stopped, so I'll try to fix them.
なかなか直んないね
It's not fixing easily...
というわけで、まずはこちらのニュースからいきたいと思います
Anyway, let's start with this first news item.
秘密結社holoX Live 2026 "First MISSION" が開催！
Secret Society holoX Live 2026 "First MISSION" to be held!
ステージなんかね、すごいよかった、都会的な感じの、なんかholoXらしいライブでしたね
The stage was really great. It had a city-like feel, a very holoX-style live show.
すごいなんか降ってきている
Whoa, there's so much falling down!
秘密結社 holoX Live 2026 『First MISSION』 が開催！
[Title: Secret Society holoX Live 2026 'First MISSION' Held!]
いや良かったと思いますね。はい。
I think it was really great. Yes.
なんか最近ねライブ、現地ライブだとね、すごい...
Lately, for lives, especially on-site lives...
...みんな一番最後に「ありがとうございました」って生の声で伝えるっていうのがね...
...at the very end, everyone saying 'Thank you' with their raw voices...
...なんかやったら流行ってて...
...has become really popular...
...みんなの喉がぶっ壊れるんじゃないかとちょっと心配はしているんですけれども。
...I'm a little worried that everyone's throats might get destroyed, though.
はい。まあやっぱり生でね、声が聞こえるっていうのは現地ならではだから...
Yes. After all, hearing voices live is something unique to being there...
...みんな嬉しいは嬉しいわよね。
...everyone is definitely happy about it.
はい、じゃあお次行きたいと思います。
Alright, I'd like to move on.
お次のニュースはこちら。
The next news is this.
ラオーラ・パンテーラ、生誕ライブを開催！
[Title: Raora Panthera to hold birthday live!]
ラオーラ、生誕ライブを開催！
Raora Panthera holds her birthday live!
ラオーラが生誕ライブをやっていました。
Raora was performing her birthday live.
詳しくはラオーラのチャンネルにて！ラオーラ可愛いね。
Details on Raora's channel! Raora is cute, isn't she?
うちも出ました。ぜひチェックしてみてください。
I also made an appearance. Please check it out.
おかゆと三人で歌いました。
I sang together with Okayu and the three of us.
お次行きたいと思います。
I'd like to move on.
モンスターハンターストーリーズ3コラボ衣装をお披露目！
[Title: IRyS reveals 'Monster Hunter Stories 3' collab outfit!]
アイリスがモンスターハンターストーリーズ3のコラボ衣装をお披露目！
IRyS reveals her Monster Hunter Stories 3 collaboration outfit!
はい。モンハンコラボね。続いております。
Yes. A Monster Hunter collab. It's continuing from before.
詳しくはアイリスのチャンネルにてということで。華やかだね。可愛い。
Details on IRyS's channel. It's so vibrant and cute.
はい、そしてお次はこちら。
And next is this.
角巻わため、新衣装をお披露目！
[Title: Tsunomaki Watame reveals new outfit!]
わためも新衣装をお披露目！
Watame also reveals a new outfit!
わためも新衣装お披露目してましたよ。
Watame was also revealing her new outfit.
詳しくはわためのチャンネルにてということで。
Details on Watame's channel.
なんかね、なんかちょい...ちょっと何か...
It was like... a little bit...
...メイドさんっぽいバージョンもあり、カジノのディーラーみたいな感じの服装にもなり...
...there's a maid-like version, and also an outfit that looks like a casino dealer...
...みたいな感じで可愛かったですね。髪型も可愛い。
...it was really cute. The hairstyle is cute too.
お次行きたいと思います。
Moving on.
お次のニュースはこちらです。
The next news is this.
holoX × セブン-イレブン コラボキャンペーンが開催中！
[Title: holoX × Seven-Eleven collab campaign is underway!]
holoXとセブンイレブンのコラボキャンペーンが開催中！
The holoX and Seven-Eleven collaboration campaign is underway!
こちらね、ライブと連動した施策となっております。ぜひチェックしてみてください。
This is an initiative linked to the live event. Please check it out.
お次はこちら。
Next is this.
『ホロライブ ガシャポンパレット』シリーズが始動、商品化が決定！
[Title: 'Hololive Gashapon Palette' series starts, production confirmed!]
ホロライブ ガシャポンパレットシリーズが始動、商品化が決定！
The Hololive Gashapon Palette series is starting, and products are confirmed!
ガシャポンパレット、これあれかな？フィギュアかな？気になりますね。
Gashapon Palette, is this maybe... figures? I'm curious.
また可愛い予感。ぜひこちらもチェックしてみてくださいね。
I have a feeling it'll be cute again. Please check this out too.
そしてお次のニュースはこちらです。
And the next news is this.
ホロどうぶつタワーバトル・トーナメントが開催！
[Title: Hololive Animal Tower Battle Tournament to be held!]
ホロライブ どうぶつタワーバトルのトーナメントが開催されました！
The Hololive Animal Tower Battle tournament was held!
どうぶつタワーバトル大会。
Animal Tower Battle tournament.
うちはちょっと用事あって出れませんでしたが。詳しくはルイのチャンネルにてということでね。
I had some errands so I didn't participate, but... details are on Rui's channel.
誰が優勝したかはぜひチェックしてみてください。
Please check to see who won.
そしてお次。
And next.
常MOS × いきなり！ステーキのコラボが決定！
[Title: TsuneMOS × Ikinari Steak collab confirmed!]
常MOSといきなりステーキコラボが開催決定！
The TsuneMOS and Ikinari Steak collaboration is confirmed!
なんとですね、まさかの常MOS案件です。
Surprisingly, it's a project for TsuneMOS.
常MOSで案件もらったの初めてなんじゃないかな？
Is this the first time TsuneMOS has gotten a sponsorship?
ちなみにですね、いきなりステーキコラボはですね、おかゆがね、逆オファーしてコラボさせてもらったのをきっかけに...
By the way, the Ikinari Steak collab started when Okayu made a reverse offer...
...定期的にコラボをさせてもらってまして、基本的にはおかゆを軸に...
...and they've been collaborating regularly since then, basically centered around Okayu...
...案件が展開するため、今回おかゆがね、参加している常MOSに...
...so because the projects develop that way, this time it was offered to TsuneMOS...
...白羽の矢が立ったみたいですね。はい。
...which Okayu is a part of. It seems the choice fell on us.
いやそうなんですよ。実はそういう流れがあるんです。
Indeed. That's how it's been flowing.
突然の案件ということで。
A sudden sponsorship.
かなり力を入れたね、店内ラッピングとかもやってくださるみたいなので、ぜひ気になる方はチェックしてみてくださいね。
They are putting quite a bit of effort into it, like in-store wrapping, so if you're interested, please check it out.
はい、では次行きたいと思います。
Alright, let's move on to the next one.
お次のニュースはこちら。
Here is the next news.
おいやーす。京都 IP 書店 × さくらみこ POPUP が開催！
[News: Kyoto IP Bookstore x Sakura Miko POPUP to be held!]
えっ、京都でさくらみこポップアップが開催中！
Um, a Sakura Miko pop-up shop is currently open in Kyoto!
ということで、はい。
And so, yes.
こちらね、みこちのね、あの、絵本がね、出たじゃないですか。
You know, Miko-chi's... well, she released a picture book recently, right?
それとね、連動したポップアップショップがあるみたいなので。
It seems there's a pop-up shop linked to that release.
これね、いいよね、なんか神社とかも作ってあるみたいですよ。
This is nice. It looks like they even set up a mini shrine or something.
みこちオンリーショップなのでね、ぜひこちらチェックしてみてください。
It's a Miko-chi only shop, so please go check it out.
すごいいっぱいパネルも置いてあってね、フィギュアもあるしね。
There are so many panels on display, and they have figures too.
なんか間違えてるけどね。
Though it looks like she made a mistake.
では次行きたいと思います。お次のニュースはこちら。
Now, moving on. Here is the next news.
ラプラス・ダークネス、とちてれアニメフェスタ2026に出演し、栃木未来大使に任命される！
[News: La+ Darkness appointed as Tochigi Future Ambassador!]
いやぁついにね、ラプちゃんが栃木の公式、えー、大使に任命されたということで。
Wow, La+ has finally been appointed as an official ambassador for Tochigi.
いや素晴らしいですね。
That's just wonderful.
いや本当念願だったよね。
It really was her long-time dream.
うちもね、あの群馬でいろんなお紹介する案件など頂きましたが。
I've also had projects where I introduced various things about Gunma, but...
大使にはまだなれていないので。
I haven't quite become an ambassador yet.
いやお先に、先を越された感があり、非常に羨ましいです。
I feel like she beat me to it, so I'm very envious.
群馬もなんかあるのかな、大使とか。
I wonder if Gunma has something like an ambassador role.
はい。ぜひラプちゃんには頑張ってほしいですね。
Yes. I really hope La+ does her best.
では次行きたいと思います。お次のニュースはこちら。
Now, moving on. Here is the next news.
常闇トワ主催、『常闇祭 2』が開催決定！
[News: Tokoyami Towa to host 'Tokoyami-sai 2'!]
ということで、これはね、えーと、トワの企画となっております。
So, this is one of Towa's own projects.
これはあれですね、6月の6日に配信で行われるということで、1ヶ月後ぐらいですか。
It will be streamed on June 6th, so in about a month's time.
また盛り上がりそうですね。はい、スト6です。はい。
It looks like it'll be exciting again. Yes, it's Street Fighter 6.
スト6の大会みたいな感じですね。こちらもチェックしてみてください。
It's like a Street Fighter 6 tournament. Please check this out too.
はい、では次行きたいと思います。
Alright, moving on to the next one.
ときのそら、9周年記念ワンマンライブ開催決定！！
[News: Tokino Sora's 9th Anniversary Solo Live decided!!]
えー前回のですね、東京国際フォーラムのライブの時に、えーと。
Um, back during her previous live at Tokyo International Forum...
まあ次はねここだよ、みたいなのは発表されていたんですが。
There was an announcement like, 'The next one will be here,' but...
しっかりとね、告知されました。
Now it's been formally announced.
こちらもね、しっかりと皆さん応援してくれたら嬉しいなという感じです。
I'd be happy if everyone could give this one their full support as well.
はい。では次参りましょう。お次のニュースはこちら。
Yes. Now, let's move on. Here is the next news.
大空スバル、ノーパンで生ケツを叩かれる！
[News: Oozora Subaru gets bare butt slapped while commando!]
まあ、生ケツを叩くは正直ノーパン関係なかったんですけどね。
Well, to be honest, slapping the bare butt had nothing to do with being commando.
なんか、自らノーパンを開示するという。
Yet somehow, she ended up disclosing it herself.
あの時のおかゆの返しも良かったんだよなぁ。
Okayu's retort at that moment was also great.
なんか何だったかな、スバルがパンツ履いてないみたいな雰囲気のこと言って。
What was it again... She hinted at Subaru not wearing any underwear.
え、ノーパンってこと？で、なんか「ちょうどいいじゃん」みたいな。
Like, 'Wait, you're commando?' and then, 'Well, that's just right.'
「ちょうどいいじゃん、手間が省けてちょうどいいじゃん」みたいな。
'It's just right, it saves you the trouble, so it's just right.'
面白かったですね。はい、ということで以上、朝ミオニュースのコーナーでした。
That was hilarious. And with that, this was the Morning Mio News corner.
はい。
Yes.
ちょうどいい...
Just right...
ちょうどいいトワ一体。
What on earth is a 'just right' Towa?
うちよりノーパンなんじゃないかスバル。
Maybe Subaru is more of a commando than I am.
うち、うちとはまた違うよな、なんか
It's a bit different from my case, I guess...
うちはさ 寝る時ノーパンなんよ 健康法で
I don't wear underwear when I sleep. For health.
寝る時ぐらいパンツから解放してあげようっていう
I figure I should free myself from them while sleeping,
自分の体を労わるためのノーパンなんですけど
going commando to take care of my body.
いや、そうなんだよね
Yeah, exactly.
なんか最近朝ミオになるとちょっと...
Lately, whenever I do AsaMio...
この時間なのかわかんないけどね、なんかズビズビなんですけど
I don't know if it's the time, but my nose is so runny.
何でなんだろう。
I wonder why.
までもさ、いいじゃんね、恥ずかしがることないじゃん。
But you know, it's fine. Nothing to be ashamed of.
パンツから解放されればいいのに。
I wish everyone could be free from underwear.
もうね、いいじゃん別に。
It's really fine, whatever.
なんかノーパンだからエッチとかないから、別に。
It's not like going commando is inherently sexual.
なんかエッチだエッチじゃない シュレディンガーのパンツ。
Sexy or not... it's like Schrodinger's underwear.
別に履いてるか履いてないかなんでさ。
It's just a matter of if they're on or not.
もちろんさ 履いてない状態でさ なんかヒラヒラのスカート履いてたりとかしたらやべーけど。
Of course, it'd be bad to go commando in a frilly skirt...
ジャージとかだったらまあどっちでもいいかみたいなところあるよな。
But with trackpants, it doesn't really matter, right?
だって普通は脱がないもん。
I mean, normally you don't take them off.
まあたまたま脱ぐ事態が発生してしまったっていうだけでさ。
It's just that the occasion to take them off happened.
シュレディンガーのパンツだよ。
It's Schrodinger's underwear.
そんなんだってさ友達とかにさ 聞かないやん
You don't go around asking your friends,
今日パンツ履いてる？とか言って。
'Are you wearing underwear today?' or anything.
だからまあいいんじゃないか、もはや。
So I guess it's fine at this point.
アメバシップありがとう
Thanks for the membership!
いやむしろ あのー 何て言えばいいんだ...
Or rather, uh... how should I put it...
まあそんなことになるとは思わなかったからね。
Well, I didn't think it would come to that.
まさかのねーって感じだし。
It was quite a surprise.
いや分かる 締め付けがね 得意じゃないっていうの分かるからさ。
I get it. I understand not liking tight clothes.
人類はパンツから解放されてもいいんじゃないかなって思いますけどねうちは。
I think humanity should just be free from underwear.
アメバシップありがとう
Thanks for the membership!
みんな解放されよ、パンツから。
Everyone, let's be free from underwear.
自由を求めろ
Seek freedom!
みんなパンツから出ていけ
Everyone, get out of your underwear!
まあ必要な時もあるよ。
Well, there are times when it's necessary.
必要な時もあるけど、履いてなくてもいい時もあるかなみたいな。
But there are also times when you don't need them.
固定概念を捨てろ
Cast aside fixed concepts!
最近なんかあれだもん... なんか見たのがそのパンツの形状でもさ、
Lately... I've seen underwear designs where,
本当お腹のところにしかゴム入ってないみたいなパンツとかあるよね。
the elastic is only at the waist.
女の子のパンツでも、なんか男性でいうトランクスみたいなやつとか
There are girl's panties that look like men's trunks,
女子のパンツでもあって...
among other styles...
何のためにパンツって履いてんだろう。
I wonder why we even wear underwear.
あまりパンツの話すぎるのはあまり良くない。
Talking about underwear too much isn't good.
いやそうなんだよ。
Yeah, it really isn't.
服が、服はいるやん。
You need clothes, obviously.
一番外側はいるけど...
You need the outermost layer...
一番内側は自分しかわからないなら、なんかいいかなみたいな。
But if I'm the only one who knows about the innermost layer, then it's fine.
どっちでもいい。
Either way is fine.
あんまり他人のパンツに興味なくない？
Besides, aren't you uninterested in other people's underwear?
そんなことないか？
Or is that not the case?
だからどっちでもよくない？って考え。
So, my thought is, either way is fine.
あれだ。興味ないからどっちでもいいんだ。
That's it. I'm not interested, so I don't care.
なるほど。うちは興味ないからどっちでもいいって思ってんだ。
I see. I feel like either way is fine because I'm not interested.
なんかノーガードとか、防御力がとか言ってるけど...
People talk about 'no-guard' or 'defensive power'...
あんな布切れ一枚で防御もクソもあるかって話で。
But with just a single piece of cloth, defense is out of the question.
そうなんですよ。
That's exactly right.
なんか、みこちが言ってたらしいね。こないだのコラボでちびりかけたみたいな話してたけど。
Apparently, Miko-chi was saying she almost peed herself during the last collab.
はっきり言わせていただいていいですか？うちも巻き込まれてたんですが...
Let me make this clear, since I was being lumped in with her...
うちはですね、下準備バッチリなのとですね...
As for me, I'm perfectly prepared.
ああいう、おそらく笑い転げるであろうコラボの際にはですね...
In those collabs where I'm likely to roll around laughing...
もし、ちょっとちびりかけても大丈夫なように。
Even if I almost pee myself, I'll be fine.
基本的には、あれを... おむつを履いているので大丈夫です。
Because basically, I'm wearing... a diaper, so it's fine.
漏らす前提かよって思ったかもしれないけど、ああいう時って思わぬことがあったりするからね。
You might think, 'Are you expecting to leak?', but unexpected things can happen.
ちゃんと、吸収するものをくっつけてるので大丈夫です。
I have something absorbent attached, so it's okay.
下準備はバッチリ。
My preparations are perfect.
パンツからは解放されるべきだと思っているけど、おむつは履いている。
I think we should be freed from underwear, but I'm wearing a diaper.
なので、心配しないでください。
So, please don't worry about me.
びしゃびしゃになるよりいいからね。
It's better than getting soaking wet.
なんでこんな下（しも）の話になってきてるんでしょうか？
Why has the conversation turned to such a crude topic?
っていうか、うちはもしかして恥じらいが足りないのでしょうか？
Come to think of it, do I lack a sense of shame?
恥じらいが、もしかして足りない？
Do I lack a sense of shame?
まさか。
No way...
スパチャありがとうございます。
Thank you for the Super Chat.
朝から何の話をされている...
What am I talking about this early in the morning?
気持ちもわかるけど、
I understand how you feel, but
やっぱり要素としてはその、音から入ってくる情報ってかなりデカいじゃないですか。
after all, the information you get from sound is a huge factor, isn't it?
あの、ちょっとさ、あの、笑いすぎて
Um, you know, like when you're laughing so hard
ちょっとお漏らししちゃったとしても、音は出ないけど。
and you leak a little bit, it doesn't make a sound.
だからオムツを履いておくという防御策は、別に普通かなと思うんだけど、
So, I think wearing a diaper as a safeguard is actually quite normal, but...
同時視聴で、鼻息がずっと入って、ずっと無言で鼻息が入ってるの恥ずかしくない？
Isn't it embarrassing when you're doing a watch-along and your breathing is picked up during long silences?
で、みんなにスピースピー言ってる、とか言われるほうが恥ずかしい。
And having everyone say you're making 'spee-spee' sleeping sounds, that's more embarrassing.
そっちのほうが恥ずかしいでしょ。
That would be way more embarrassing, right?
あー、音の問題だね、どっちかっていうと。
Ah, it's more of a sound issue, really.
いや、そう、呼吸音というか、なんか...
Yeah, like breathing sounds, or something...
ま、マイクが、その、感度がめちゃくちゃいいから。
Well, my microphone's sensitivity is incredibly high.
スパチャありがとう。あの、マイク感度が良すぎて、
Thanks for the Super Chat. Um, the mic sensitivity is so high
全くの無音で喋ってないと、その、呼吸の音とかがすごい入りやすくなるというか。
that if I'm not talking and it's silent, my breathing sounds get picked up really easily.
聞こえやすくなるのよね、めっちゃ。喋ってるときはそんなに、あれだけど。
You can hear it so clearly. It's not so noticeable when I'm actually talking, though.
だからさ、なんかそれが、恥ずかしいよな。
So, you know, that's what's embarrassing.
いや、そう、だからみこちがさ、あの、睡眠配信した、寝配信したとき。
Yeah, so when Mikochi did her sleep stream...
本当にうちは、心配してたの。なんか、いろんな音が聞こえてしまうんじゃないかと思ってさ。
I was really worried. I thought all sorts of sounds might be picked up.
なんかそれやるって聞いたとき、本人にも言ったわけよ。「え、ヤバいんじゃないの？大丈夫？」
When I heard she was going to do it, I told her directly, "Wait, isn't that dangerous? Are you okay?"
「めちゃくちゃいろんな音が自分の身体から出てるかもしれんやん。寝てるときわかんないやん、そんなん。」
"All sorts of sounds might come from your body. You wouldn't even know since you're asleep."
「どうする？」っつって。
"What are you going to do?" I said.
思ったんだけどね。でもそれもさらけ出す、勇気はすごいなと思うよ。
That's what I thought. But I think her courage to expose all that is amazing.
うちは自分のこと信用できないから、できないわ。
I can't trust myself like that, so I could never do it.
寝てる最中にどんなことしでかすかわかんないもん。無理かも。うちは無理かも。
I have no idea what I might do while I'm asleep. It's impossible for me.
いや、そう寝言でさ、突然住所とか言い出したらヤバいじゃん、だって。
I mean, if I suddenly blurted out my address in my sleep, it would be a disaster.
100%起こらないとは言い切れないじゃん。
You can't say for sure that it won't happen.
電話番号言っちゃった、とかさ。
Like, "Oh no, I said my phone number!"
いや、無意識ヤバい。
Yeah, the unconscious mind is scary.
怖いーわ。
It's terrifying.
ねー。
Right?
いや、そう、そう、お父さんとかお母さんの名前の本名言っちゃった、とかさ。
Yeah, exactly, like accidentally saying your parents' real names.
恐ろしいですね。
That's scary, isn't it?
ま、でも、おもしろかったけどね、あれはあれで。でもみこちにしかできないんじゃないかな。
Well, it was funny in its own way. But I think it's only something Mikochi can pull off.
いや、だから、音の要素やっぱデカいから、っていう話ですよ。
So yeah, I'm just saying the sound factor is really significant.
同時視聴が、嫌なの。
That's why I'm wary of watch-alongs.
嫌だっていうか、恥ずかしい。
Not exactly "wary", more like embarrassed.
できない、同時視聴。
I just can't do watch-alongs.
ふぅー。
Phew.
お腹空いたから、そろそろ終わりにします。
I'm hungry, so I'm going to wrap this up soon.
お腹空きすぎた。なんか食べようっと。
I'm starving. I'm going to go eat something.
今日もちゃんと起きることができたぞ。いや、今年調子いいな。
I managed to wake up properly today too. Man, I'm on a roll this year.
...いいからね。今のところ寝坊してないから。
...since I haven't overlept so far.
上半期寝坊せずに終われるかもしれん。
I might be able to finish the first half of the year
without oversleeping.
うち寝言結構言うらしい。だから怖いんだよ。
I heard I talk in my sleep quite a bit.
That's why it's scary.
うち寝言結構言うらしいよ。
I heard I talk in my sleep quite a bit.
恐ろしい。なんて言ってるんだろう自分。
Terrifying. I wonder what I'm saying.
はい、というわけで、来週の朝ミオお便りのテーマは
So, the theme for next week's Asa Mio letters is...
生活リズムの正し方ということでね。
...'How to fix your lifestyle rhythm'.
5月病吹き飛ばせ、生活リズムを正して、
Let's blow away the May blues, fix our lifestyle rhythm,
明るく楽しく元気よく生きていきましょう。
and live brightly, happily, and energetically.
はい、では皆さんありがとうございました。また来週お会いしましょう。
Okay, then thank you everyone.
Let's meet again next week.
それでは、おつみおーん！お腹空いた！
And with that, Otsumiooon! I'm hungry!
おつみおーん！
Otsumiooon!
うち、うち、うちだよ。大神ミオだよ。
It's me, me, it's me. I'm Ookami Mio.
Thank you for watching!
[Text: Thank you for watching!]
チャンネル登録よろしくね。
Please subscribe to my channel.
こっちだよって。ねえ。
Over here. Hey.
また見てね！
Watch again!
もなちゃん、ありがと。
Mona-chan, thanks.
え、嘘でしょ。お刺身ってこと？
Eh, you're kidding. You mean sashimi?
うわ～、そうなんだ。なんでだろう。
Wow, I see. I wonder why.
あ～、大変だ。
Ah, it's tough.
じゃあね、バイバイ！また来てね！
Bye now! Come again!